<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Essays on Alex Brogan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essays on Alex Brogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.9</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advice you most need to hear</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-advice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Life advice is useful when it resonates emotionally and logically. It’s useful when it changes your behaviour. It is true that not all life advice is useful over time. What’s useful now may not be useful in 10 years. What was useful 5 years ago, isn’t useful now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;For this reason, periodically assessing the ‘advice you most need to hear’ and keeping that front of mind is pivotal to becoming the highest version of yourself. If you are already performing in alignment with a given set of advice, you don’t need to remind yourself of specific advice. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agency is your ability to shape circumstances</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-agency-is-your-ability-to-shape-circumstances/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-agency-is-your-ability-to-shape-circumstances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Agency is your ability to shape circumstances instead of being shaped by them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Most people live their entire lives as spectators. They watch others build companies, create movements, and change history. They attribute success to luck, timing, or privilege. &lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;This is a comforting illusion that protects their ego.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The truth is simpler and harder to accept: agency is a choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Every billionaire, world-changer, and history-maker made this choice. They decided they wouldn&#39;t accept the world as given. They would bend reality instead. This isn&#39;t mystical — it&#39;s mechanical. You either believe your actions matter or you don&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Career things I&#39;d tell my younger self</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-career/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Brand names (Stripe, Anthropic, Goldman Sachs, McKinsey) are optional, but they do imply positive traits that people will take you seriously for.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t get a brand name, you can still imply your capabilities in a permissionless way through the internet. Create content. Create apps. Build things people want. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/noahkagan_a-few-months-ago-a-high-schooler-sent-me-activity-7195134321655955456-xsdX/&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Apprentice under someone impressive&lt;/a&gt; by sending them a cold email.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Work insanely hard in your 20’s.&lt;/strong&gt; Weekends are a social construct popularised by Henry Ford in the early 20th century to encourage people to travel more (so they would use his cars). Do with this information what you will.&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matthew_effect&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t compare your 1st iteration to someone else&#39;s 100th</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-dont-compare-your-1st-iteration-to-someone-elses-100th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-dont-compare-your-1st-iteration-to-someone-elses-100th/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The grandstand&#39;s metal seat sears through my shorts as I sit alone, sweat beading on my forehead, my pulse racing in sync with the ripples in the pool below. Serbia’s July sun beats down mercilessly, but it&#39;s not just the heat that&#39;s making my palms clammy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;It&#39;s 2012. I&#39;m 15, and it&#39;s my first time overseas without a parent. I&#39;m with my club water polo team in Belgrade for a training camp before the National Championships. We’re at Partizan, arguably the world’s most famous club, known for its long list of Olympians.&amp;nbsp; I’m excited to test myself against the best. I rate myself. How good could they be? I started playing water polo 4 years ago. Between swimming, gym, and actual sessions, I’ve been training up to 13 times a week. It’s all I do and think about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great leaders don&#39;t just manage people</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-great-leaders-dont-just-manage-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-great-leaders-dont-just-manage-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The chlorine-scented air stings my nostrils as I catch my breath, my arms draped over the pool&#39;s edge, water lapping gently against my chest. The sun glints off the surface, but it&#39;s not the light that&#39;s making me squint – it&#39;s the anticipation of what&#39;s about to unfold. It&#39;s April 2013. I&#39;m training with the Western Australian State School Boys team ahead of the National Championships in June. It&#39;s our first session, and my coach, Andrew, is splitting the squad into two teams for a practice game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can some people get so lucky in life?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-can-some-people-get-so-lucky-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-can-some-people-get-so-lucky-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;We often think that luck is about being in the right place at the right time. But the surest way in life to find luck is much easier. What follows is the story of how the most powerful woman in startups creates &#39;luck&#39; out of thin air.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Ann Miura-Ko (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.threads.net/@annimaniac&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;@annimaniac&lt;/a&gt;) has been labelled the most powerful woman in start-ups by Forbes. She is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;A co-founding partner of Floodgate Venture Capital&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;An early investor and board member in Lyft&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;A lecturer in entrepreneurship at Stanford&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;And a world-class debater&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure id=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-center&#34; data-rt-type=&#34;image&#34; data-rt-align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/63fd511e232de229bfe66c52/67243cb46ac5b5a57eed93a6_369543311_821418839644908_980179348643754008_n.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Alex Brogan on August 23, 2023.&#34; width=&#34;auto&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; loading=&#34;auto&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Ann’s parents came to America seeking opportunity having grown up in post-WW2 Japan. They had almost no money, spoke very little English, and had no support system when they arrived. What they did have was a steely grit and determination to make a life in America. Her father worked intensely to receive a PhD in mechanical and aerospace engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the world might look in 30 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-predictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;By 2030&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;AI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;AI will surpass human capabilities in all healthcare diagnostic tasks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;AI will be smarter than a Nobel Prize winner across biology, programming, math, engineering, writing and have access to all the interfaces available to a human working virtually, including text, audio, video, mouse and keyboard control, and internet access&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;AI-powered personal assistants became capable of generating entire new movies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;AI will automate AI research, compressing decades of progress into single years&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;AI will displace up to 30 percent of our workforce resulting in 400 to 800 million job losses&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to choose the highest leverage activities to work on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-to-choose-the-highest-leverage-activities-to-work-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-to-choose-the-highest-leverage-activities-to-work-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;To increase your leverage, ask yourself before any activity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;How could I complete this task in a fraction of the time to the same standard? (decrease time cost)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;What is the expected (confidence x ROI) impact of this task? (increase value)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;What else could I be doing that&#39;s higher leverage? (opportunity cost)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;To identify your highest leverage task, ask:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;If I could only do one thing for the rest of the week that would have the greatest impact, what would it be?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to find your life&#39;s work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-to-find-your-lifes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-to-find-your-lifes-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Arguably, the best thing &lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/strong&gt; ever said:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;“The only way to be truly satisfied is to do what you believe is great work. And the only way to do great work is to love what you do. If you haven’t found it yet, keep looking. Don’t settle. As with all matters of the heart, you’ll know when you find it.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/em&gt;The problem? Most of us don’t know where to look...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to read anyone’s character instantly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-to-read-anyones-character-instantly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-to-read-anyones-character-instantly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;(1) Observe Their Partner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Who people choose to partner with says more than anything they say. It tells us more about their desires, assumptions, and needs than anything else. It indicates their priorities and values, as well as what they think of themselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;(2) Observe How They Handle No&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Rejection is a big part of life. Those who take &#34;No&#34; poorly usually have an overinflated sense of entitlement. The world owes no one anything. Those who accept and live by this are people you can share bad news with easily.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How you do anything is how you do everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-you-do-anything-is-how-you-do-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-how-you-do-anything-is-how-you-do-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;My lungs feel like they&#39;re on fire as I collapse onto the page-white sand, each breath a desperate gasp that tastes of salt and exhaustion. The Indian Ocean stretches before me, a vast blue expanse that seems to mock my spent body, while the merciless sun beats down above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;It&#39;s 2012, and I&#39;ve just completed another gruelling run-swim-run as a surf life saving cadet. As a year 10 student, I&#39;m part of a group of fifty cadets who&#39;ve chosen surf life saving as our extra-curricular activity. Every Friday afternoon, we face the same challenge: an 800-meter sand run, followed by a 500-meter swim, and another 400-meter sand run to finish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I had a conversation with a billionaire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-i-had-a-conversation-with-a-billionaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-i-had-a-conversation-with-a-billionaire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;3 months ago, I had a short conversation with a billionaire. I asked for their book recommendations, but I got a lesson I’ll remember for the rest of my life. They told me that they don’t give advice or mentorship. That they’ve never received any value from it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;They shared the view that other people’s advice is often from their own unique experience and is often wrong or at least much less valuable when applied to your own circumstance. They said that instead of seeking advice they had “read a lot and studied and experimented and failed and learned and then finally succeeded.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you’re not curious, you’ll never be great</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-if-youre-not-curious-youll-never-be-great/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-if-youre-not-curious-youll-never-be-great/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The elevator doors slide shut, sealing me in with my dreams and doubts. It&#39;s 2019, and I&#39;m ascending to the 30th floor of Goldman Sachs, my heart racing faster than the lift itself. At 21, with the dust of European cobblestones and South American trails still clinging to my shoes following a gap year, I&#39;ve landed what many consider the holy grail of finance jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Despite my excitement, I&#39;m acutely aware of how little I know. I create an extensive list of resources to learn: financial modelling, valuation techniques, industry primers – you name it. Over the next few months, I immerse myself in the material alongside my full-time job. I&#39;m learning rapidly, and although it&#39;s not always visible, I&#39;m improving quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing returns to focus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-increasing-returns-to-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-increasing-returns-to-focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Many people advocate for building “Range” in your career, but this is wrong. People who have built phenomenal careers with outsized returns do not do this. Instead, they do one thing at incredible depth for an astoundingly long time. In the next few decades, those who do this stand to profit even more than they have in the past. We’re entering the era of “increasing returns to focus.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life is short and fleeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-life-is-short-and-fleeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-life-is-short-and-fleeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The antiseptic smell of the hospital corridor hit me as I rushed towards my father&#39;s room, my heart pounding in my chest. It’s September 9, 2009, and just moments ago, I had been sitting quietly in the back row of my school chapel during a weekly assembly. I’m 12, an idealistic kid with a keen grasp of life’s possibilities. A never-ending sense of time. And a playful demeanor with a curiosity for life’s playground. But, for the last 6 months, my Dad has been in a stoic battle with cancer. And it’s finally getting the better of him. It’s spread to his liver. And it’s terminal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Others&#39; reactions to you reveal their relationship with themselves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-others-reactions-to-you-reveal-their-relationship-with-themselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-others-reactions-to-you-reveal-their-relationship-with-themselves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Others&#39; reactions to you reveal their relationship with themselves, not your worth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;People&#39;s behavior rarely has anything to do with you. It&#39;s projection. A mirror of their inner world. Most take it personally anyway. When someone lashes out, we instinctively believe we caused it. We didn&#39;t. Their reaction comes from somewhere else entirely. Some unresolved pain. Some private battle you know nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The moment you see others&#39; behavior as their own internal struggle externalized, you gain freedom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation kills anxiety</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-preparation-kills-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-preparation-kills-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;I’m sweating profusely in fear and anxiety. It’s June 2015, I’m sitting in an exam room—the classic gymnasium filled with plastic chairs and wooden desks wall-to-wall, shoulder to shoulder.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s my intro to Finance exam, notoriously difficult. It’s only 15 minutes in but it feels like it’s been an hour. I can&#39;t focus. It feels like time is standing still. Thoughts rush through my mind: &#34;There&#39;s no way I&#39;m going to pass this. If I don&#39;t, I might fail the unit, and it&#39;s going to be a blemish on my record forever. Why is this exam so hard?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problems worth thinking about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Agriculture&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Feeding 10 billion people by 2050 is a huge challenge (food)&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Feeding 10 billion people by 2050 is a monumental challenge. We need to produce more food in the next 30 years than in all of human history. This requires a shift in how we grow food, as arable land is decreasing due to erosion—over half has likely been lost since agriculture began. Fossil fuel dependence for fertilizers poses another risk, highlighted by soaring food prices after the Ukraine crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shelves of books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Republic-Plato/dp/0140449140&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Republic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Nicomachean-Ethics-Aristotle/dp/0872204642&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Nicomachean Ethics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/48499610-ego-is-the-enemy&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Ego is the Enemy: The Fight to Master Our Greatest Opponent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/48592071-stillness-is-the-key&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Stillness is the Key: An Ancient Strategy for Modern Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/48592055-the-obstacle-is-the-way&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The Obstacle is the Way: The Timeless Art of Turning Adversity to Advantage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4069.Man_s_Search_for_Meaning&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Man’s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/As-One-Free-Mind-Conditioning/dp/1890772623&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;As One is: To Free the Mind from All Conditioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Atmamun-Achieving-Himalayan-Swamis-Freedom/dp/1532762720&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Freedom-Known-J-Krishnamurti/dp/0060648082&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Freedom from the Known&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Book-Life-Jiddu-Krishnamurti/dp/0060648791/ref=pd_lpo_d_sccl_2/356-2067001-6278343?pd_rd_w=VWoXt&amp;content-id=amzn1.sym.7ef4c059-30c9-4984-b131-e38134d0b653&amp;pf_rd_p=7ef4c059-30c9-4984-b131-e38134d0b653&amp;pf_rd_r=1RH3H1V03A9Y4B7XTW02&amp;pd_rd_wg=eLBvb&amp;pd_rd_r=e0c1f6f9-76f1-4b9d-8612-c6b7efd08ef2&amp;pd_rd_i=0060648791&amp;psc=1&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The Book of Life: Daily Meditations with Krishnamurti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Think-These-Things-J-Krishnamurti/dp/0060916095/ref=sr_1_1?crid=12JMGFUSLSUAF&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.zL073vz4WR3Zki02v1oqDPht91ymeMhfH9LMgxUo1jhYpN4vD0yqaq6RixTN2StCcwWksxBh5l1PFxOi489wkvB8hFKZWDXHPaocpZ2VE3KvW5X7lsesPw4oJR73j_RxKSqm_pXg9xNhR8fQQrhuZWe1F9keFbigKXAyS50o9YFTiaGDiZ6Njlxcbd1_I6W-2SChvNIuAALmTIRKUsY1fWxTNbE2kaQ-Z7-TnvH8cnM.SYoP-0iCt1wYBE_whsMFPkJOPCGcgKGQx8_NrRVVxSU&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=think+on+these+things&amp;qid=1732409029&amp;s=books&amp;sprefix=think+on+these+thin,stripbooks,273&amp;sr=1-1&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Think on These Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Atmamun-Achieving-Himalayan-Swamis-Freedom/dp/1532762720&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Atmamun: The Path to a Phenomenal Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Overcoming-World-Kapil-Gupta/dp/B0BSLJ8YKZ&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Overcoming-World-Kapil-Gupta/dp/B0BSLJ8YKZ&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Overcoming the World: The Unpublished Teachings of Kapil Gupta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Masters-Secret-Whispers-Those-Living/dp/1975841689&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Masters-Secret-Whispers-Those-Living/dp/1975841689&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;A Master&#39;s Secret Whispers: For Those Who Abhor Noise and Seek The Subtle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Direct-Truth-Uncompromising-non-prescriptive-questions/dp/1724334417&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Direct-Truth-Uncompromising-non-prescriptive-questions/dp/1724334417&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Direct Truth: Uncompromising, non-prescriptive Truths to the enduring questions of life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/gp/product/B00NPBH4AU/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_d_asin_title_o07aud_?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Status Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Four-Thousand-Weeks-Embrace-Limits/dp/B09234FXHM/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1CIF2S3Y8GFCY&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.rbInxda6vZyPhVxCZcN57e3vTF0CANVqTMWfttqC2kUIUgwTyR7KeltoPAUr_2ZHJjVomW1M1k5qHI-5BMYdRTf9XtXfGdLW5YvslJaXJ-BPELsXByNfjB4IxkM6NmhFxRP4nrqSsmJAkfWSaNVXkI2JP829g--2nfcmTJbeA55-9WMtQ-9iWZ741j34CAPWOGM2RSCop2LPWAFQ1kcQiokAJbdEDJVh5i4TDG8xg54.rX21r3vZjZIG1ShYg4_FzVHICBGanY8fgqZhVCiFz20&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=four+thousand+weeks&amp;qid=1732410038&amp;s=audible&amp;sprefix=four+thousand+wee,audible,307&amp;sr=1-1&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.au/Four-Thousand-Weeks-Embrace-Limits/dp/B09234FXHM/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1CIF2S3Y8GFCY&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.rbInxda6vZyPhVxCZcN57e3vTF0CANVqTMWfttqC2kUIUgwTyR7KeltoPAUr_2ZHJjVomW1M1k5qHI-5BMYdRTf9XtXfGdLW5YvslJaXJ-BPELsXByNfjB4IxkM6NmhFxRP4nrqSsmJAkfWSaNVXkI2JP829g--2nfcmTJbeA55-9WMtQ-9iWZ741j34CAPWOGM2RSCop2LPWAFQ1kcQiokAJbdEDJVh5i4TDG8xg54.rX21r3vZjZIG1ShYg4_FzVHICBGanY8fgqZhVCiFz20&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=four+thousand+weeks&amp;qid=1732410038&amp;s=audible&amp;sprefix=four+thousand+wee,audible,307&amp;sr=1-1&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Four Thousand Weeks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systems I use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Physical &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;mental health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Exercise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;1x daily morning walk 20 mins (heart rate optimisation during the walk between — 100-120 BPM (median heart rate)&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QFIduNAi6MfecOSL2ujQuLnE6qIQpN_nwgvfLLIZKVw/edit?gid=0#gid=0&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;4x weight sessions upper/lower body + 1x HIIT session&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Work with personal trainer for accountability+better results&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1mFcIsCWM5XCwtkzWXFMUyjjI0JGWknRxOZJTe_dP9r8/edit?usp=sharing&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Diet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1mFcIsCWM5XCwtkzWXFMUyjjI0JGWknRxOZJTe_dP9r8/edit?usp=sharing&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Slow Carb Diet&lt;/a&gt;‍&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Avoid sugars/heavy carb meals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Avoid alcohol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Athletic greens 1x daily&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Intermittent supplements incl. Nootropics&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Fasting. 2x/month - 2 days. 4x/year - 4 days&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Sleep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;7.5 hours of sleep per night&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eightsleep.com/au/&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Eight Sleep&lt;/a&gt; for sleeping comfort&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Melatonin for getting back in sleep rhythm and/or adjusting to timezones&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fastest learners are unburdened by embarrassment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-the-fastest-learners-are-unburdened-by-embarrassment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-the-fastest-learners-are-unburdened-by-embarrassment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The fastest learners are unburdened by embarrassment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Think about the last time you were learning something new — a language, a sport, or a skill. Did you hold back from asking questions or practicing in front of others out of fear of looking foolish? Most do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;As Thomas Newkirk put it:&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#34;Embarrassment is a true enemy of learning.&#34;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;It blocks full engagement with the learning process. It stops us from making the mistakes that growth demands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fruits of reading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-the-fruits-of-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-the-fruits-of-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Knowledge acquisition is a gross underestimation of the fruits of reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;There is a saying, “Kill two birds with one stone.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Reading is closer to “Kill a flock with a rock.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;A non-exhaustive list of the benefits of reading:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Find inspiration &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Heightened empathy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Broadened vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Knowledge acquisition&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Solve others’ problems &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Prevent others’ mistakes &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Prevent your own mistakes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Improved written communication &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Improved verbal communication &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Solve your own problems more efficiently&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Cultivate the habit of sustained attention&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Increased creativity by allowing you to combine ideas&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Meditation-like benefits of quietening the monkey mind &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Add depth and meaning to everyday interactions with more raw material&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;A greater capacity for meaningful interactions with a wider range of people&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;When you’re justifying reading more, remember that it’s not just knowledge acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The high-return activity of raising others’ aspirations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-the-high-return-activity-of-raising-others-aspirations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-the-high-return-activity-of-raising-others-aspirations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;I was coached by an eight-time Olympian.&lt;/strong&gt; A lesson he taught me will stick with me for life. In 2011, I was 3 years into my junior water polo career. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;I&#39;d been playing for the Dolphins when the coach of a competitor club and 8-time Australian Olympian, Tom Hoad, asked me to join his team and travel to Europe that Winter. Little did I know that this was the first step in one of the most rewarding adventures of my teens—and an introduction to an idea that will stick with me for life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The whole world is insecure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-the-whole-world-is-insecure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-the-whole-world-is-insecure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The aroma of bacon and coffee wafts through the air, a stark contrast to the weighty conversations unfolding around me. It’s July 2024, I’m sitting in a large conference room with endless round tables eating a hot breakfast alongside mediocre, hotel-calibre coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Sitting next to me is a ~40 year-old man named Toby. Toby sold his business for over $400m three years ago. I’m sharing my experience building a social media audience, what it was like getting started, and how it’s changed my life.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We judge ourselves by what we know we’re capable of</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-we-judge-ourselves-by-what-we-know-were-capable-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-we-judge-ourselves-by-what-we-know-were-capable-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The clink of silverware against plates suddenly stops, replaced by a stunned silence that surrounds the table. Heads turn, eyes widen, and the woman next to me nearly chokes on her coffee, her hand frozen midway to her mouth. It’s July 2024 and I’m sitting in a conference room in Victoria, Canada, eating a hot breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;On my left is a ~40 year-old man named Toby who sold his business for $400m three years ago. I can’t believe the words that have just come out of his mouth. It feels like I’m in a movie. Is this guy a comedian? I lean in with intrigue, thinking that he’s about to tell me he’s joking. I wonder what he’s going to say next.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I learned at Goldman Sachs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-what-i-learned-at-goldman-sachs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-what-i-learned-at-goldman-sachs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;1. High agency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;High-agency people happen to the world; the world doesn’t happen to them. They take ultimate responsibility and see everything as a problem to be solved with creative solutions. If they haven’t solved a problem before, they speak to someone who has or find an answer. They never ask, “How do I do this?” without first trying to answer that themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;2. High-speed communication&lt;/strong&gt;‍&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Let’s be real: Communication is a core part of any role. Those who respond quickly are people we consider to have their “sh*t” together. This is no different in the workplace. Speed demonstrates attentiveness and conscientiousness—two critical predictors of success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What trait do 9/10 billionaires credit for their success?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-what-trait-do-9-10-billionaires-credit-for-their-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2025-07-02-what-trait-do-9-10-billionaires-credit-for-their-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;What trait do 9/10 billionaires credit for their success? “Agency” Here’s what it is and how you can develop it…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure id=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-center&#34; data-rt-type=&#34;image&#34; data-rt-align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/63fd511e232de229bfe66c52/66fcf9e9f9f4b328f750b2dd_66fcf7fb80f35ea40cbc9718_X%2520tweet%2520image.jpeg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;__wf_reserved_inherit&#34; width=&#34;auto&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Agency is influencing the external environment to shape it in your favour. It’s moving from passive receiver of circumstances to active shaper of reality. It’s rejecting the world&#39;s status quo and making a new world instead. It’s removing the word “No” from your vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;It’s acting on impulses that hide behind shadows of fear, doubt, and comparison. It’s noticing something that isn’t right and having the courage to make it so. It’s changing history by sheer force of will. Agentic people happen to the world; the world doesn’t happen to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
