<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Alex Brogan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Alex Brogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.9</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>15 Of The Best Decision-Making Mental Models I&#39;ve Found</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-15-of-the-best-decision-making-mental-models-ive-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-15-of-the-best-decision-making-mental-models-ive-found/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;15 Of The Best Decision-Making Mental Models I&#39;ve Found&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;1) The Inside-Outside View&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;We have a natural tendency to favour the inside view—our own independent solution to a problem that incorporates all of our hidden biases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;To make better decisions, we should favour the outside view—one that incorporates the best available data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure id=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-center&#34; data-rt-type=&#34;image&#34; data-rt-align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/63fd511e232de229bfe66c52/640fabb4817e749fd7d9b716_FSKzmT0X0AAeLbl.jpeg&#34; id=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;auto&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; loading=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;2) Ladder of Inference&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Describes the thinking process we go through—often subconsciously—to get from a fact to a decision or action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Things I&#39;ve Learned In 25 Years of Living</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-31-things-ive-learned-in-25-years-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-31-things-ive-learned-in-25-years-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;1. Ask for what you want in an assertive manner, just make sure you have the runs on the board. Know your worth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;2. Be unreasonably interested in other people when you are meeting and getting to know them. Ask questions, be attentive and engaged. Just make sure it doesn’t become an interrogation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;3. Don’t take things personally, unless of course someone has deliberately set out to get you. There are a myriad of reasons why people can act in a way that negatively affects you. It’s not always a personal attack. In most cases, what’s happening in someone else’s life is far more important to them and will determine their actions&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Principles Of Effective Web Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-5-principles-of-effective-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-5-principles-of-effective-web-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Laborum iusto officia nihil laborum dolorem.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ipsum nemo rerum omnis est temporibus sequi. Sed et temporibus ut deleniti nemo. Sit voluptas harum nihil delectus hic aperiam. Repellat qui sequi ut dolores pariatur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Eum facere eum eos.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Assumenda ex non quia. Quis ad dolorem mollitia cumque. Commodi ut alias id ullam quo rem.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Totam autem doloribus facilis ullam explicabo incidunt. Ab corrupti ducimus eum occaecati est nesciunt non est dolorem. Cupiditate dicta ut earum quaerat similique voluptatem est. Neque beatae deserunt consequuntur non aliquid sequi neque qui. Quo quasi est sapiente sed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Few Of My Favourite Parables</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-a-few-of-my-favourite-parables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-a-few-of-my-favourite-parables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;To Change The World&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;When I was a young man, I wanted to change the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;I found it was difficult to change the world, so I tried to change my nation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;When I found I couldn’t change the nation, I began to focus on my town. I couldn’t change the town and as an older man, I tried to change my family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Now, as an old man, I realize the only thing I can change is myself, and suddenly I realize that if long ago I had changed myself, I could have made an impact on my family. My family and I could have made an impact on our town. Their impact could have changed the nation and I could indeed have changed the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Framework To 10x Your Network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-a-simple-framework-to-10x-your-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-a-simple-framework-to-10x-your-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;A simple framework to 10x your network&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Help This Person&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Every time you encounter another person, think: &lt;strong id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#34;How can I help this person?&#34;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;It&#39;s not altruistic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Nothing else can so quickly accelerate your career and improve your quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Being helpful is the best form of &#34;self-promotion&#34; there is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;When you see someone you&#39;d rather not spend time talking to, think &#34;help this person.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Instead of giving short answers and trying to end the conversation abruptly, genuinely ask how they are and what they&#39;re working on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A System For Learning Intelligently</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-a-system-for-learning-intelligently/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-a-system-for-learning-intelligently/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;A system for learning intelligently&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Learning how to learn is one of life’s most important skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Here’s how you can do it intelligently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;1. Learning Selection&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Have you ever started learning something only to stop a few days or weeks later?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;This can happen for lots of reasons, but often it&#39;s bad learning selection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Selecting what you learn and when you learn it is crucial to maintaining motivation to finish it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Here are some questions to make sure you&#39;re choosing well:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Master Uncomfortable Conversations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-how-to-master-uncomfortable-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-how-to-master-uncomfortable-conversations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Fast Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Difficult conversations are a necessary evil both in and out of the workplace. We can’t skip them, so instead, we must learn to navigate them positively. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;To tackle uncomfortable conversations, we need to first use an integrative mindset, which allows us to adapt and remain neutral when faced with difficulty. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Acknowledging our own discomforts, managing our emotions, and adjusting our communication approach is key to handling difficult conversations with ease. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Next time you have a difficult conversation, focus on your goals and intentions. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;&#34;&gt;When we master difficult conversations, we command respect from our peers, gain confidence, and, most importantly, get what we want. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure id=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-center&#34; data-rt-type=&#34;image&#34; data-rt-align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/63fd511e232de229bfe66c52/64316a887e38fba2a4fc210e_image.png&#34; id=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;auto&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; loading=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;&#34;&gt;Throughout my early career, I struggled to engage in difficult conversations, especially those that stretched my comfort zone, involved crucial feedback, or addressed poor performance either from myself or others. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Crow and the Pitcher by Aesop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-the-crow-and-the-pitcher-by-aesop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-the-crow-and-the-pitcher-by-aesop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;“On a hot summer day, a thirsty crow flew around searching for water. It had been a long day, and the crow was growing increasingly desperate. Finally, it came across a pitcher with a small amount of water at the bottom. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;The crow tried to reach the water, but the pitcher was too deep and its neck too narrow for the crow to fit its beak inside.Feeling disheartened, the crow could have given up and continued searching for water elsewhere. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dog And His Reflection by Aesop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-the-dog-and-his-reflection-by-aesop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/2025-07-02-the-dog-and-his-reflection-by-aesop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;A Dog, to whom the butcher had thrown a bone, was hurrying home with his prize as fast as he could go. As he crossed a narrow footbridge, he happened to look down and saw himself reflected in the quiet water as if in a mirror. But the greedy Dog thought he saw a real Dog carrying a bone much bigger than his own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em id=&#34;&#34;&gt;If he had stopped to think he would have known better. But instead of thinking, he dropped his bone and sprang at the Dog in the river, only to find himself swimming for dear life to reach the shore. At last he managed to scramble out, and as he stood sadly thinking about the good bone he had lost, he realized what a stupid Dog he had been.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
